<?xml version="1.0"?>
<articles>
	<article>
		<title>Does the Verizon iPhone fix the "death grip?"</title>
		<source>MacNN</source>
		<author>Electronista Staff</author>
		<like>LIKE</like>
		<body>AntennaSys president and antenna engineer Spencer Webb believes Apple has redesigned the antenna on the Verizon iPhone 4 not just to accommodate the change to CDMA from GSM, but also to solve a problem that has famously plagued Apple (even though other smartphones suffer the same issue) -- the "grip of death." Webb, quoted in a ComputerWorld article, says there is "evidence" that the change in the antenna bands -- evidenced by the new fourth "gap" and the different placement of the gaps -- could show that Apple has solved the issue by employing a second cellular ante...</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>The Latest in iOS 4.3 and iPad 2 Rumors</title>
		<source>iPhone.AppStorm</source>
		<author>Joshua Johnson</author>
		<body>Even though the torture of several years of Verizon iPhone rumors is now thankfully over, there has still been plenty of discovery and speculation floating around on the web the past few days regarding iOS 4.3 and the upcoming iPad 2.  Buckle your seatbelt, it looks like the wizards of Infinite Loop have another great round of tricks up their sleeve to change everything once again.   More Gestures  As iOS 4.3 began to make its way into the hands of certain privileged individuals, it immediately became apparent that Apple had completely overhauled the way you interact with the iPad by adding a number of new gestures.  One new gesture allows you to perform a four or five finger pinch that will exit out of any app and return to the home screen (the same action as the current home button). Another allows you to swipe with four fingers to switch between open apps, finally when the same four finger swipe is performed in an upward motion, the multi-tasking menu slides into sight from the bottom of the screen.  MacRumors recently posted a video that shows these gestures in action. No word yet on whether we’ll see these implemented on the iPhone as well (they’ll be much more natural on the iPad’s large screen).  No Home Button!?   Will Apple ditch the home button?  Speculation is running wild now that Apple is adding gestures that functionally eliminate the need for a home button and reports are pouring in that Apple is indeed planning on removing the home button from future iOS devices.  If the rumors are true, this is definitely an interesting move for Apple and I’m quite interested to see how customers react to losing one of the few physical buttons on these devices. Presumably, the only way to wake up an iOS device will now be to hit the sleep button on the top.  Also, there’s going to be a huge usability hit for new users. The home button is friendly, intuitive and easy to spot. A four finger pinching gesture? Not so much. What do you think? Is this is a good move?  That Pesky Mute Button  While we’re on the subject of buttons, Apple made tons of customers really angry when they repurposed the orientation lock button on the iPad by turning it into a mute button.  It looks like iOS 4.3 will ease these complaints by providing an option in preferences to use the button for either muting the device or locking the orientation (source).  iPad 2 Has Cameras? Duh.  It comes as no surprise that the certainty of the iPad 2 being equipped with cameras is growing every day. Leaked case designs hint at rear and front facing cameras. Further, new UI images found hidden inside iOS 4.3 point to both photo and video capabilities and maybe even a new effects system similar to that in Photo Booth on the Mac.  As we’ve mentioned before on AppStorm, you can bet the new iPad will have FaceTime video conference capabilities due to Apple’s all out drive to increase the number of FaceTime ready devices.  If you’re interested, OneIndia has posted a video that’s supposed to be of a non-functioning display version of the new iPad. In all likelihood, the video is a complete fake, but still worth a look.  More on iOS 4.3  Before we close, there are two more things worth noting about iOS 4.3. The first is a new feature called “Find My Friends” reported by Mashable and various other sources. The true functionality of this feature isn’t currently known but everyone’s best guess is a MobileMe location service that allows you to see the current location of various friends.  Finally, iOS 4.3 brings with it the ability to setup your iPhone as a mobile hotspot, just as we saw announced with the new Verizon iPhone. Unfortunately for some users, this feature will still have to be supported by individual carriers. So just because the functionality is there, doesn’t mean AT&amp;T customers will be able to use the feature any time soon.  What Have You Heard?  That’s just about everything we’ve heard from putting our ears to the ground over the last week. As expected, the new iPad will definitely be a must-have device and the new gestures and other 4.3 benefits are just icing on the cake.  Now it’s your turn to share some dirt. Leave a comment below and tell us what you’ve heard and/or what you predict about the next iOS, iPhone, iPad or anything else Apple related.  Image Source: Flickr Creative Commons</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>comScore: Verizon iPhone likely to shake up competition</title>
		<source>MacNN</source>
		<author>The Macintosh News Network</author>
		<body>The arrival of the iPhone on Verizon could disrupt Android's current rising trend in the US while also giving the carrier customers it would much prefer, comScore determined today. Noting that Apple's US share has stayed mostly flat in the past year, it expected the second carrier to give &quot;even greater competition.&quot; Analysts stopped short of predicting how much share Apple would take....</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Too Late</title>
		<source>Daring Fireball</source>
		<author>John Gruber</author>
		<body>Dan Lyons, writing for The Daily Beast’s Newsweek subsidiary, says “The Verizon iPhone Is Too Late”:  Most important, Android still has one huge advantage over the iPhone — diversity. Android phones are sold by dozens of hardware makers, the biggest being Samsung, Motorola, and HTC. There are lots of different form factors. Slider phones. Phones with keyboards. Big screens, small screens, midsize screens.  The iPhone, in contrast, is a bit like the situation people once had with Henry Ford’s Model T, where you could have any color you wanted, as long as it was black. With the iPhone you can have whatever Steve Jobs says you can have.  The Model T was a massive hit, dominating the market for over a decade: Wikipedia says:  By 1918, half of all the cars in the US were Model T’s.  Lyons goes on to tell the story of why he himself switched from the iPhone to Android: because of Verizon’s superior network service:  Frankly, I didn’t care whether Android could match an iPhone feature-for-feature. All I cared was that I could get a smart phone that ran on Verizon and therefore could successfully make phone calls. But since then I’ve become hooked. I’ve grown used to the Android way of doing things. I’ve built my life around Google programs — Gmail, Google contacts, Google calendar, Google Maps. I love the built-in voice navigation.  So who cares that now Apple will sell its phone on Verizon? For me, it’s too late. Other converts to Team Android tell me they’re feeling the same way. “I’m not going back either,” says Fred Wilson, who runs Union Square Ventures, a venture-capital firm in New York.  So everyone on Verizon is already an Android user? There’s a big difference between the iPhone being too late to get Dan Lyons’s business, and being too late to rack up, say, 15 million Verizon sales by the end of 2011. Given the number of Verizon users who have never purchased a smartphone, his story sounds like exactly the reason the Verizon iPhone is going to be a smashing success.  But Apple’s big weakness is its control-freak nature and insistence that there is only one way to make a smart phone. No matter how many carriers sign on to carry the iPhone, in the long run, Apple has again set itself up to be a niche player in smartphones, just as it is in PCs.  I’ll just point out that he posits as fact that “Apple’s control-freak nature” is a weakness. Control-freak does carry a negative connotation in our culture. Swap in the word perfectionist and it changes the connotation. Where is the evidence that Apple’s control-freak/perfectionist nature has hurt Apple in the market — for phones, for iPods, or for computers? “We’re going to make these decisions for you and offer a limited number of choices” is indeed the company’s philosophy. That’s called design. Apple is indeed more focused on design than its competitors. It’s also been far more successful than its competitors over the past decade, in several lucrative markets.  So I’d say what Lyons calls “Apple’s big weakness” is in fact precisely the company’s biggest strength. And what about Apple’s “niche player” status in PCs? Apple is the leading PC maker in the world, by profit. And their market share has gone up for 19 consecutive quarters, and continues to outpace the industry as a whole. Apple’s “niche” in the PC market today is that for profitable computers.  The worst years for Apple’s PC business occurred when Apple was the least control-freakish: when they offered a plethora of hardware models (Performas, Centrises, Quadras) and even licensed their OS to clone makers.  I can’t decide whether Lyons is really this wrong, or if The Daily Beast makes its writers post eye-rollingly contrarian stuff like this just to get links.</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Inside the Details of the Verizon iPhone Deal</title>
		<source>Just Another iPhone Blog</source>
		<author>Alex Jordan</author>
		<body>Bloomberg has published an interesting piece wherein they spoke with Verizon President Lowell McAdam regarding the Verizon iPhone deal.  McAdam confirms that Apple and Verizon worked very closely together do bring the product to market. For instance, the Verizon cell towers seen on Apple’s campus last July were indeed there to help with the testing of the CDMA iPhone. Engineers from both companies worked together, with on top Verizon engineer even working at Apple HQ for a year, and Apple engineers were given their own laboratory to use at Verizon’s headquarters.  As for the negotiations themselves, they were carried out by Mr. McAdam and Apple COO Tim Cook. Apple CEO Steve Jobs, and Verizon CEO Ivan Seidenberg were called into the discussions as needed, but were largely absent.  “We probably worked six or nine months on the technical side of this and saw we could make this work,” he said. “Then we did the commercial side. The commercial deal took us a day.”  What I found to be the most interesting part of the report, was the agreement that Apple and Verizon came to regarding Verizon logos on the device. Verizon likes to put their logo on handsets, but according to McAdam, this wasn’t a problem for them in coming to an agreement with Apple.  “They don’t put a lot of logos on their phones,” McAdam said in the interview. “So that wasn’t a major issue for us.”  Nothing terribly shocking, but it is a surprisingly transparent account of what went on between the two companies in bring the iPhone to Verizon. Many were getting hung up on Verizon’s tendency to put their logo on handsets, and feared that this would be a point of contention for the two companies. Something small like that wasn’t going to stop this from happening, and Verizon was in the losing position. They wanted the iPhone, and if the exclusion of their logo is what sealed the deal, the logo was good as gone.</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Twitter For Mac’s Spectacular Hidden Little Feature: Tweet Anything From Anywhere</title>
		<source>TechCrunch</source>
		<author>MG Sieger</author>
		<body>I love Twitter for Mac. Love it. It has completely altered my day-to-day workflow. And it has changed the way I use Twitter itself. And that was before I found out about this killer little hidden feature today: Tweet from anywhere. I don’t know how I missed it before, but apparently installing Twitter for Mac adds a new “Tweet” command to basically a ton of apps running in OS X. MacStories first pointed this out earlier today, and now I can’t get enough. For example, if you’re browsing the web in Safari or Chrome, highlight a word or passage and right-click. At the bottom of the drop-down, you’ll see the “Tweet” command. Hitting it will populate a tweet for you with the highlighted section. And it works in TextEdit, iChat, Calendar, Mail, etc. If you read it, you can tweet it. One thing I wish it did in web browser was automatically add a link as well as the text you’re highlights, but baby-steps. I have a feeling that will come. And yes, plenty of plug-ins have had this ability for a while, but now it’s system-wide. It’s as if Twitter is now baked into OS X.</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Twitter for Mac: Impressions The First(s)</title>
		<source>Just Another iPhone Blog</source>
		<author>Thomas</author>
		<body>If you’ve been looking for an interesting new Mac app to check out, try Twitter for Mac (Free). It’s got a fresh and very different design, and it might be the kind of Mac App design we’ll be seeing more of come OS X Lion. It was supposed to be released as Tweetie 2 for Mac in the days before third-party Tweetie developer Loren Brichter became first party developer Loren Brichter of Twitter, and buyers of the MacHeist Nano Bundle 2 (from a whiiile back) were supposed to get an exclusive sneak peek at the beta before everybody else did. Tweetie 2 for Mac and the sneak peek never really happened (though Nano Bundle 2 buyers did get “secret options“), but we can probably put all that behind us now that Twitter for Mac is finally here. First of all, the app now updates in real-time … or refreshes so fast that it feels like it. If Twitter for Mac is to be seen as the successor to Tweetie, that’s a pretty big (and welcome) change. The other changes…well, they’re interesting. ￼ What I can say is that Twitter is going to take a little while to get used to. The side bar is basically the top bar, and that’s how you’re going to drag the app around.  The various tabs of the app — tweets, mentions, etc. — can be clicked on, selected with [Cmd + a number from one to six], or simply scrolled through with a three-finger swipe from your trackpad. The app also supports three-finger horzontal swipes (two-finger on a magic mouse) to go backwards, forwards, or launch a link in your browser. The app tends to reward exploring and playing, but it also doesn’t feel quite as “natural” as all the best iOS apps do. One example of this is the changes in the way you tweet. You can still Cmd + N to bring up a new tweet, but standard buttons for URL shortening or adding media are simply gone. Instead, you can now drag-and-drop pictures into a tweet (you still get to select the picture service in Preferences), and links will simply auto-shorten themselves as you publish them (no choice is given here). I don’t mind the drag-and-drop support because I’m used to that in other apps, but I’m not really a fan of how all the control over my links is taken away within the app. I’d like the power to decide whether to provide a complete or shortened link. I can probably get over that, though (or Twitter could address it in an update *hint hint*), because, provided that this new toy doesn’t take up too many of my system resources, I find myself growing rather fond of Twitter for Mac. It’s an extremely shiny little app with a very playful and daringly different interface that’s simply a lot of fun to explore and use. That being said, I definitely wouldn’t mind a manual, just to make sure I’m not missing out on any little goodies.</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Steve Jobs Granted Second Medical Leave of Absence</title>
		<source>Just Another iPhone Blog</source>
		<author>Alex Jordon</author>
		<body>Apple has issued an announcement stating that CEO Steve Jobs has been granted a medical leave of absence, and Tim Cook will be taking over the day-to-day activities at the company while Jobs is gone. Apple CEO Steve Jobs today sent the following email to all Apple employees: Team, At my request, the board of directors has granted me a medical leave of absence so I can focus on my health. I will continue as CEO and be involved in major strategic decisions for the company. I have asked Tim Cook to be responsible for all of Apple’s day to day operations. I have great confidence that Tim and the rest of the executive management team will do a terrific job executing the exciting plans we have in place for 2011. I love Apple so much and hope to be back as soon as I can. In the meantime, my family and I would deeply appreciate respect for our privacy. Steve No word on when Jobs plans to return. Of course, we’ve all heard the story. Jobs was diagnosed with pancreatic cancer in, and made a full recovery back in 2004. However, in January of 2009, Jobs announced that he would be taking an extended medical leave of absence. Only later was it discovered that Jobs had received a liver transplant during his leave. Now, the New York Time is reporting that Jobs has been experiencing “ups and down” that accompany an organ transplant, and has been taking less of an active roll in the company as he’s been experiencing one of those troughs. Here’s an excerpt: Mr. Jobs suffers from immune system issues common with people who have received liver transplants and, as a result, his health suffers from frequent “ups and downs,” according to a person with knowledge of the situation, who agreed to speak on condition of anonymity because he was not authorized to discuss it. In recent weeks, Mr. Jobs began a down cycle and slowed his activities at Apple, the person said. Mr. Jobs has been coming to the office about two days a week, and appeared increasingly emaciated, the person said. He frequently lunched in his office, rather than in the company cafeteria, the person said. So, I’m going to take the liberty, on behalf of everyone here at iSource, and wish Mr. Jobs a speedy and full recovery.</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Steve Jobs Takes Another Medical Leave of Absense - Andy Ihnatko Reminds Us of the Proper Response</title>
		<source>Just Another iPhone Blog</source>
		<author>PatrickJ</author>
		<body>Just in case you just woke up and have not already heard this news, here is Apple’s press statement this morning: Apple CEO Steve Jobs today sent the following email to all Apple employees: Team, At my request, the board of directors has granted me a medical leave of absence so I can focus on my health. I will continue as CEO and be involved in major strategic decisions for the company. I have asked Tim Cook to be responsible for all of Apple’s day to day operations. I have great confidence that Tim and the rest of the executive management team will do a terrific job executing the exciting plans we have in place for 2011. I love Apple so much and hope to be back as soon as I can. In the meantime, my family and I would deeply appreciate respect for our privacy. Steve I couldn’t agree more with Andy Ihnatko’s thought on how we should react to this: Any reaction to this has to begin and end with “Let’s all hope that this husband and father comes out of (whatever this is) OK.” In fact, let’s make that the middle of this, too.</body>
	</article>
	
	<article>
		<title>Apple: Steve Jobs Taking A Medical Leave Of Absence</title>
		<source>iPhone Hacks</source>
		<author>iPhoneHacks</author>
		<body>Apple has just issued a media advisory to reveal that Steve Jobs, co-founder and CEO is taking a medical leave of absence from the company. Steve Jobs will continue to be the CEO and involved in strategic decisions. Apple’s COO Tim Cook will oversee the day to day operations in Steve Jobs absence. Apple issued [...]</body>
	</article>
</articles>